[{"question":"What is the name of the current king of Canada?","answer":0,"options":[{"label":"King Charles the Third","value":0},{"label":"King Charles the Second","value":1},{"label":"King Charles the First","value":2},{"label":"King Charles the Fourth","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/oath-citizenship.html"},{"question":"Who does the oath of citizenship swear allegiance to?","answer":0,"options":[{"label":"His Majesty King Charles the Third","value":0},{"label":"The Constitution of Canada","value":1},{"label":"The Aboriginal and treaty rights of First Nations, Inuit and Métis peoples","value":2},{"label":"The laws of Canada","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/oath-citizenship.html"},{"question":"What is the meaning of the oath of citizenship?","answer":2,"options":[{"label":"To be loyal to Canada's laws and constitution","value":0},{"label":"To observe the Aboriginal and treaty rights of First Nations, Inuit and Métis peoples","value":1},{"label":"To be faithful and bear true allegiance to King Charles the Third and his successors","value":2},{"label":"To fulfill the duties of a Canadian citizen","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/oath-citizenship.html"},{"question":"What represents all Canadians in the oath of citizenship?","answer":1,"options":[{"label":"A constitution","value":0},{"label":"The Sovereign (Queen or King)","value":1},{"label":"A flag","value":2},{"label":"The country of Canada","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/oath-citizenship.html"},{"question":"What are the sources of Canadian law?","answer":2,"options":[{"label":"Laws passed by Parliament and the provincial legislatures, the civil code of France, English common law and the Magna Carta","value":0},{"label":"Laws passed by Parliament and the provincial legislatures, the civil code of England, English common law and the Charter of Rights and Freedoms","value":1},{"label":"Laws passed by Parliament and the provincial legislatures, English common law, the civil code of France and the unwritten constitution inherited from Great Britain","value":2},{"label":"Laws passed by Parliament and the provincial legislatures, the civil code of England, the Magna Carta and the Charter of Rights and Freedoms","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/rights-resonsibilities-citizenship.html"},{"question":"Which of the following is not a fundamental freedom outlined in the Charter of Rights and Freedoms?","answer":0,"options":[{"label":"Freedom of conscience and religion","value":0},{"label":"Freedom of thought, belief, opinion and expression","value":1},{"label":"Freedom of peaceful assembly","value":2},{"label":"Freedom of association","value":3},{"label":"Freedom of speech and of the press","value":4}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/rights-resonsibilities-citizenship.html"},{"question":"What does the Constitution of Canada entrench?","answer":3,"options":[{"label":"The Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms","value":0},{"label":"The Magna Carta","value":1},{"label":"The unwritten constitution","value":2},{"label":"The principles that recognize the supremacy of God and the rule of law","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/rights-resonsibilities-citizenship.html"},{"question":"What do the Mobility Rights in the Charter of Rights and Freedoms guarantee?","answer":0,"options":[{"label":"Canadians can live and work anywhere they choose in Canada, enter and leave the country freely, and apply for a passport","value":0},{"label":"Canadians can freely choose their religious beliefs and express their opinions without interference","value":1},{"label":"French and English have equal status in Parliament and throughout the government","value":2},{"label":"French language rights for linguistic minorities","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/rights-resonsibilities-citizenship.html"},{"question":"What are some of the additional rights outlined in the Charter of Rights and Freedoms?","answer":4,"options":[{"label":"Aboriginal Peoples’ Rights and Official Language Rights","value":0},{"label":"Multiculturalism and Official Language Rights","value":1},{"label":"Aboriginal Peoples’ Rights and Official Language Rights","value":2},{"label":"Aboriginal Peoples’ Rights and Mobility Rights","value":3},{"label":"Official Language Rights and Minority Language Educational Rights","value":4}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/rights-resonsibilities-citizenship.html"},{"question":"Which of the following is NOT a responsibility of Canadian citizenship?","answer":5,"options":[{"label":"Obeying the law","value":0},{"label":"Taking responsibility for oneself and one’s family","value":1},{"label":"Serving on a jury","value":2},{"label":"Voting in elections","value":3},{"label":"Helping others in the community","value":4},{"label":"Paying taxes","value":5}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/rights-resonsibilities-citizenship.html"},{"question":"What does serving on a jury require?","answer":3,"options":[{"label":"It is not required but it is optional","value":0},{"label":"Serving on a jury is a privilege that makes the justice system work as it depends on impartial juries made up of citizens","value":1},{"label":"It is required by law and failure to serve may result in a fine or imprisonment","value":2},{"label":"When called to do so, you are legally required to serve","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/rights-resonsibilities-citizenship.html"},{"question":"Why is volunteering considered important in Canada?","answer":5,"options":[{"label":"Volunteering is a mandatory requirement for Canadian citizenship","value":0},{"label":"Volunteering helps individuals gain useful skills and develop friends and contacts","value":1},{"label":"Volunteering is a source of income for many Canadian charities","value":2},{"label":"Volunteering is a way to avoid paying taxes","value":3},{"label":"Volunteering helps build a sense of community and promotes harmonious living","value":4},{"label":"All of the above","value":5}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/rights-resonsibilities-citizenship.html"},{"question":"What is a way to protect Canada and contribute to the community?","answer":1,"options":[{"label":"Serving in the regular Canadian Forces (navy, army, and air force)","value":0},{"label":"Serving in the local part-time navy, militia, and air reserves","value":1},{"label":"Getting involved in the cadets","value":2},{"label":"Serving in the Coast Guard or emergency services","value":3},{"label":"All of the above","value":4}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/rights-resonsibilities-citizenship.html"},{"question":"What are Canadian citizens responsible for protecting?","answer":2,"options":[{"label":"Canada's natural resources","value":0},{"label":"Canada's economic interests","value":1},{"label":"Canada’s natural, cultural and architectural heritage","value":2},{"label":"Canada's political system","value":3},{"label":"Canada's national parks","value":4}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/rights-resonsibilities-citizenship.html"},{"question":"What is Canada's oldest continuous constitutional tradition?","answer":3,"options":[{"label":"Being a constitutional monarchy","value":0},{"label":"Upholding a commitment to Peace, Order, and Good Government","value":1},{"label":"Belief in ordered liberty, enterprise, hard work, and fair play","value":2},{"label":"Being known as a strong and free country","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/who-are-canadians.html"},{"question":"Who are the three founding peoples of Canada?","answer":0,"options":[{"label":"Aboriginal, French, and British","value":0},{"label":"Inuit, Métis, and Acadian","value":1},{"label":"English, French, and Scottish","value":2},{"label":"Anglophones, Francophones, and Ukrainians","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/who-are-canadians.html"},{"question":"What are the three distinct groups of Aboriginal peoples?","answer":2,"options":[{"label":"Inuit, Métis, and First Nations","value":0},{"label":"Indian, Inuit, and Métis","value":1},{"label":"Indian, Inuit, and Métis","value":2},{"label":"First Nations, Inuit, and Acadians","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/who-are-canadians.html"},{"question":"Which province is officially bilingual?","answer":3,"options":[{"label":"Quebec","value":0},{"label":"Ontario","value":1},{"label":"Manitoba","value":2},{"label":"New Brunswick","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/who-are-canadians.html"},{"question":"How many Anglophones live in Canada?","answer":1,"options":[{"label":"7 million","value":0},{"label":"18 million","value":1},{"label":"30 million","value":2},{"label":"65%","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/who-are-canadians.html"},{"question":"What is the largest religious affiliation in Canada?","answer":1,"options":[{"label":"Muslims","value":0},{"label":"Catholics","value":1},{"label":"Jews","value":2},{"label":"Hindus","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/who-are-canadians.html"},{"question":"Which group of people do not enjoy full protection and equal treatment under the law in Canada?","answer":0,"options":[{"label":"Gay and lesbian Canadians","value":0},{"label":"Christians","value":1},{"label":"Muslims","value":2},{"label":"Jews","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/who-are-canadians.html"},{"question":"What is Canada often referred to as?","answer":2,"options":[{"label":"A land of immigrants","value":0},{"label":"A constitutional monarchy","value":1},{"label":"A bilingual country","value":2},{"label":"A multicultural society","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/who-are-canadians.html"},{"question":"What is the meaning of the Remembrance Day poppy?","answer":3,"options":[{"label":"To remember our Sovereign, Queen Elizabeth II","value":0},{"label":"To celebrate Confederation.","value":1},{"label":"To honour prime ministers who have died","value":2},{"label":"To remember the sacrifice of Canadians who have served or died in wars up to the present day","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/who-are-canadians.html"},{"question":"What are three responsibilities of citizenship?","answer":1,"options":[{"label":"Being loyal to Canada, recycling newspapers, serving in the navy, army or air force","value":0},{"label":"Obeying the law, taking responsibility for oneself and one’s family, serving on a jury","value":1},{"label":"Learning both official languages, voting in elections, belonging to a union.","value":2},{"label":"Buying Canadian products, owning your own business, using less water.","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/who-are-canadians.html"},{"question":"Who was the first explorer to draw a map of Canada’s East Coast?","answer":1,"options":[{"label":"John Cabot","value":0},{"label":"Jacques Cartier","value":1},{"label":"Lord Durham","value":2},{"label":"Sir Wilfrid Laurier","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/canadas-history.html"},{"question":"What is the name of the French frigate that led the captured USS Chesapeake into Halifax harbour in 1813?","answer":3,"options":[{"label":"HMS Shannon","value":0},{"label":"HMS Chesapeake","value":1},{"label":"HMS Victory","value":2},{"label":"HMS Saladin","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/canadas-history.html"},{"question":"When did Canada officially become a self-governing Dominion?","answer":2,"options":[{"label":"July 1, 1867","value":0},{"label":"January 1, 1901","value":1},{"label":"July 1, 1868","value":2},{"label":"January 1, 1931","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/canadas-history.html"},{"question":"Who led the Canadian Corps in the capture of Vimy Ridge?","answer":0,"options":[{"label":"General Sir Arthur Currie","value":0},{"label":"Major-General Sir Isaac Brock","value":1},{"label":"Lieutenant-Colonel John McCrae","value":2},{"label":"Major-General Robert Ross","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/canadas-history.html"},{"question":"When did women in Canada win the right to vote in federal elections?","answer":1,"options":[{"label":"1916","value":0},{"label":"1918","value":1},{"label":"1920","value":2},{"label":"1925","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/canadas-history.html"},{"question":"What treaty opened up Canada's trading policies in the postwar era?","answer":0,"options":[{"label":"General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT)","value":0},{"label":"North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO)","value":1},{"label":"North American Aerospace Defence Command (NORAD)","value":2},{"label":"United Nations (UN)","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/modern-canada.html"},{"question":"Who painted the forests and Aboriginal artifacts of the West Coast?","answer":1,"options":[{"label":"Emily Carr","value":0},{"label":"Pauline Johnson","value":1},{"label":"Louis Hémon","value":2},{"label":"Émile Nelligan","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/modern-canada.html"},{"question":"Who invented the telephone?","answer":0,"options":[{"label":"Alexander Graham Bell","value":0},{"label":"Joseph-Armand Bombardier","value":1},{"label":"Sir Sandford Fleming","value":2},{"label":"Mathew Evans and Henry Woodward","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/modern-canada.html"},{"question":"Who invented the snowmobile?","answer":1,"options":[{"label":"Alexander Graham Bell","value":0},{"label":"Joseph-Armand Bombardier","value":1},{"label":"Sir Sandford Fleming","value":2},{"label":"Mathew Evans and Henry Woodward","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/modern-canada.html"},{"question":"Who invented the world system of standard time zones?","answer":2,"options":[{"label":"Alexander Graham Bell","value":0},{"label":"Joseph-Armand Bombardier","value":1},{"label":"Sir Sandford Fleming","value":2},{"label":"Mathew Evans and Henry Woodward","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/modern-canada.html"},{"question":"Who invented the first electric light bulb?","answer":3,"options":[{"label":"Alexander Graham Bell","value":0},{"label":"Joseph-Armand Bombardier","value":1},{"label":"Sir Sandford Fleming","value":2},{"label":"Mathew Evans and Henry Woodward","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/modern-canada.html"},{"question":"Who invented the radio?","answer":4,"options":[{"label":"Alexander Graham Bell","value":0},{"label":"Joseph-Armand Bombardier","value":1},{"label":"Sir Sandford Fleming","value":2},{"label":"Mathew Evans and Henry Woodward","value":3},{"label":"Reginald Fessenden","value":4}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/modern-canada.html"},{"question":"Who invented the first cardiac pacemaker?","answer":6,"options":[{"label":"Alexander Graham Bell","value":0},{"label":"Joseph-Armand Bombardier","value":1},{"label":"Sir Sandford Fleming","value":2},{"label":"Mathew Evans and Henry Woodward","value":3},{"label":"Reginald Fessenden","value":4},{"label":"Dr. Wilder Penfield","value":5},{"label":"Dr. John A. Hopps","value":6},{"label":"SPAR Aerospace / National Research Council","value":7},{"label":"Mike Lazaridis and Jim Balsillie","value":8}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/modern-canada.html"},{"question":"Who invented the Canadarm?","answer":7,"options":[{"label":"Alexander Graham Bell","value":0},{"label":"Joseph-Armand Bombardier","value":1},{"label":"Sir Sandford Fleming","value":2},{"label":"Mathew Evans and Henry Woodward","value":3},{"label":"Reginald Fessenden","value":4},{"label":"Dr. Wilder Penfield","value":5},{"label":"Dr. John A. Hopps","value":6},{"label":"SPAR Aerospace / National Research Council","value":7},{"label":"Mike Lazaridis and Jim Balsillie","value":8}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/modern-canada.html"},{"question":"Which wireless communications company is known for inventing the BlackBerry?","answer":8,"options":[{"label":"Alexander Graham Bell","value":0},{"label":"Joseph-Armand Bombardier","value":1},{"label":"Sir Sandford Fleming","value":2},{"label":"Mathew Evans and Henry Woodward","value":3},{"label":"Reginald Fessenden","value":4},{"label":"Dr. Wilder Penfield","value":5},{"label":"Dr. John A. Hopps","value":6},{"label":"SPAR Aerospace / National Research Council","value":7},{"label":"Mike Lazaridis and Jim Balsillie","value":8}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/modern-canada.html"},{"question":"What are the three key facts about Canada's system of government?","answer":0,"options":[{"label":"It is a federal state, a parliamentary democracy, and a constitutional monarchy","value":0},{"label":"It is a federal state, a socialist democracy, and a constitutional monarchy","value":1},{"label":"It is a unitary state, a parliamentary democracy, and a constitutional monarchy","value":2},{"label":"It is a unitary state, a socialist democracy, and a constitutional monarchy","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/how-canadians-govern-themselves.html"},{"question":"What are the responsibilities of the federal government in Canada?","answer":2,"options":[{"label":"Municipal government, education, health, natural resources","value":0},{"label":"Navigation, currency, criminal law, citizenship","value":1},{"label":"Defence, foreign policy, interprovincial trade and communications","value":2},{"label":"Property, civil rights, highways","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/how-canadians-govern-themselves.html"},{"question":"What is the role of the Prime Minister in Canada's government?","answer":1,"options":[{"label":"Selecting the Senators and representing the Sovereign","value":0},{"label":"Selecting the Cabinet ministers and directing the policy of the government","value":1},{"label":"Voting on bills and monitoring expenditures","value":2},{"label":"Approving new laws and maintaining the confidence of the House","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/how-canadians-govern-themselves.html"},{"question":"What is the role of the Sovereign in Canada's government?","answer":3,"options":[{"label":"Directing the operations and policy of the government","value":0},{"label":"Selecting the Senators and approving new laws","value":1},{"label":"Representing the Prime Minister and directing the governing of the country","value":2},{"label":"Playing a non-partisan role and being the focus of citizenship and allegiance","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/how-canadians-govern-themselves.html"},{"question":"What is the difference between the head of state and the head of government in Canada's government?","answer":0,"options":[{"label":"The head of state is the Sovereign, who is non-partisan, while the head of government is the Prime Minister, who directs the governing of the country","value":0},{"label":"The head of state is the Prime Minister, who directs the governing of the country, while the head of government is the Sovereign, who is non-partisan","value":1},{"label":"The head of state is the Governor General, who represents the Sovereign, while the head of government is the Premier, who directs the governing of the province","value":2},{"label":"The head of state is the Premier, who directs the governing of the province, while the head of government is the Governor General, who represents the Sovereign","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/how-canadians-govern-themselves.html"},{"question":"What is the role of the Lieutenant Governor in each province of Canada?","answer":2,"options":[{"label":"Representing the Prime Minister and directing the governing of the province","value":0},{"label":"Approving new laws and maintaining the confidence of the Assembly","value":1},{"label":"Representing the Sovereign and appointing the Lieutenant Governor","value":2},{"label":"Selecting the Cabinet ministers and directing the policy of the government","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/how-canadians-govern-themselves.html"},{"question":"What is the minimum age to run in a federal election?","answer":2,"options":[{"label":"16 years old","value":0},{"label":"20 years old","value":1},{"label":"18 years old","value":2},{"label":"25 years old","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/federal-elections.html"},{"question":"Who produces the voters' lists used during federal elections and referendums?","answer":3,"options":[{"label":"The Prime Minister","value":0},{"label":"The Governor General","value":1},{"label":"Members of Parliament","value":2},{"label":"Elections Canada","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/federal-elections.html"},{"question":"How often are federal elections held?","answer":0,"options":[{"label":"Every four years","value":0},{"label":"Every two years","value":1},{"label":"Once a year","value":2},{"label":"Every six years","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/federal-elections.html"},{"question":"What can nobody do when you vote in Canada?","answer":2,"options":[{"label":"Watch you vote","value":0},{"label":"Ask you who you voted for","value":1},{"label":"Look at how you voted","value":2},{"label":"Discuss how you voted with others","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/federal-elections.html"},{"question":"Who becomes the Prime Minister after an election?","answer":1,"options":[{"label":"The leader of the political party with the most seats in the House of Commons","value":0},{"label":"The leader of the political party with the second most seats in the House of Commons","value":1},{"label":"The leader of the political party with the third most seats in the House of Commons","value":2},{"label":"The leader of the political party that wins the popular vote","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/federal-elections.html"},{"question":"What is the principle of the Canadian justice system?","answer":1,"options":[{"label":"Presumption of guilt","value":0},{"label":"Presumption of innocence","value":1},{"label":"Presumption of punishment","value":2},{"label":"Presumption of guilt until proven innocent","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/justice-system.html"},{"question":"What are the three branches of the Canadian justice system?","answer":3,"options":[{"label":"Police, lawyers, judges","value":0},{"label":"Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP), Federal Court, Supreme Court","value":1},{"label":"Municipal police, provincial police, lawyers","value":2},{"label":"Supreme Court, Federal Court, provincial courts","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/justice-system.html"},{"question":"Who enforces federal laws throughout Canada?","answer":2,"options":[{"label":"Municipal police departments","value":0},{"label":"Provincial police forces","value":1},{"label":"Royal Canadian Mounted Police (RCMP)","value":2},{"label":"Federal Court","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/justice-system.html"},{"question":"What can lawyers help you with?","answer":0,"options":[{"label":"Legal problems and representing you in court","value":0},{"label":"Providing legal aid services","value":1},{"label":"Punishing criminals and deterring crime","value":2},{"label":"Enforcing the law","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/justice-system.html"},{"question":"What is the symbol of government in Canada?","answer":3,"options":[{"label":"The Canadian Crown","value":0},{"label":"The Maple Leaf","value":1},{"label":"The Red Ensign","value":2},{"label":"The Mace of the House of Commons","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/canadian-symbols.html"},{"question":"What are the two official languages of Canada?","answer":0,"options":[{"label":"English and French","value":0},{"label":"English and Spanish","value":1},{"label":"French and German","value":2},{"label":"English and Chinese","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/canadian-symbols.html"},{"question":"What is Canada's best-known symbol?","answer":1,"options":[{"label":"The Red Ensign","value":0},{"label":"The Maple Leaf","value":1},{"label":"The Snowbirds","value":2},{"label":"The Royal Arms of Canada","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/canadian-symbols.html"},{"question":"What is the highest honour available to Canadians?","answer":2,"options":[{"label":"The Order of Canada","value":0},{"label":"The Polar Medal","value":1},{"label":"The Victoria Cross","value":2},{"label":"The Order of Merit","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/canadian-symbols.html"},{"question":"When is Canada Day celebrated?","answer":2,"options":[{"label":"January 1","value":0},{"label":"April 9","value":1},{"label":"July 1","value":2},{"label":"November 11","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/canadian-symbols.html"},{"question":"When is Remembrance Day celebrated?","answer":3,"options":[{"label":"January 1","value":0},{"label":"April 9","value":1},{"label":"July 1","value":2},{"label":"November 11","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/canadian-symbols.html"},{"question":"What are the three main types of industries in Canada's economy?","answer":2,"options":[{"label":"Transportation, healthcare, tourism","value":0},{"label":"Manufacturing, agriculture, mining","value":1},{"label":"Service industries, manufacturing industries, natural resources industries","value":2},{"label":"Technology, education, retail services","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/canadas-economy.html"},{"question":"How did Canada's trading relationship with the United States change in 1988?","answer":0,"options":[{"label":"Canada enacted free trade with the United States","value":0},{"label":"Canada closed its borders to the United States","value":1},{"label":"Canada became a partner in NAFTA with the United States","value":2},{"label":"Canada's exports to the United States decreased","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/canadas-economy.html"},{"question":"What is the size of Canada's economy compared to other countries?","answer":1,"options":[{"label":"It is the largest economy in the world","value":0},{"label":"It is one of the ten largest economies in the world","value":1},{"label":"It is smaller than most other economies in the world","value":2},{"label":"It is the second largest economy in the world","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/canadas-economy.html"},{"question":"Which industry provides the most jobs in Canada?","answer":2,"options":[{"label":"Manufacturing industry","value":0},{"label":"Natural resources industry","value":1},{"label":"Service industries","value":2},{"label":"Technology industry","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/canadas-economy.html"},{"question":"What is the largest trading partner of Canada?","answer":0,"options":[{"label":"United States","value":0},{"label":"Mexico","value":1},{"label":"Germany","value":2},{"label":"Japan","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/canadas-economy.html"},{"question":"What are the five distinct regions of Canada?","answer":0,"options":[{"label":"Atlantic Provinces, Central Canada, Prairie Provinces, West Coast, Northern Territories","value":0},{"label":"Maritime Provinces, Heartland, Prairie Provinces, Pacific Coast, Northern Territories","value":1},{"label":"Atlantic Canada, Ontario, Quebec, Great West, North","value":2},{"label":"Newfoundland and Labrador, Ontario, Quebec, Alberta, Yukon","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/canadas-regions.html"},{"question":"Which region is known for its vineyards, wines, and fruit crops?","answer":2,"options":[{"label":"Maritime Provinces","value":0},{"label":"Atlantic Canada","value":1},{"label":"Prince Edward Island","value":2},{"label":"Central Canada","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/canadas-regions.html"},{"question":"What is the capital city of Quebec?","answer":0,"options":[{"label":"Québec City","value":0},{"label":"Montreal","value":1},{"label":"Toronto","value":2},{"label":"Ottawa","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/canadas-regions.html"},{"question":"What is the largest city in Canada?","answer":1,"options":[{"label":"Quebec City","value":0},{"label":"Toronto","value":1},{"label":"Montreal","value":2},{"label":"Ottawa","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/canadas-regions.html"},{"question":"Which region is known for its oil and gas production?","answer":2,"options":[{"label":"Central Canada","value":0},{"label":"Prairie Provinces","value":1},{"label":"Alberta","value":2},{"label":"West Coast","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/canadas-regions.html"},{"question":"According to Section 5 of the Citizenship Act, who does the Minister grant citizenship to?","answer":0,"options":[{"label":"Any person who has an adequate knowledge of Canada and the responsibilities and privileges of citizenship.","value":0},{"label":"Only Canadian residents who have lived in Canada for a certain number of years.","value":1},{"label":"Only Canadian citizens who have made significant contributions to the country.","value":2},{"label":"Only individuals with a high level of education and professional qualifications.","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/authorities.html"},{"question":"Based on Section 15 of the Citizenship Regulations, what subjects must a person have a general understanding of to have an adequate knowledge of Canada?","answer":2,"options":[{"label":"Canadian political parties, Canadian holidays, Canadian provinces and territories.","value":0},{"label":"Canadian sports, Canadian music, Canadian literature.","value":1},{"label":"Canadian political and military history, Canadian social and cultural history, Canadian physical and political geography.","value":2},{"label":"Canadian cooking, Canadian fashion, Canadian art.","value":3}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/authorities.html"},{"question":"What is one of the responsibilities of citizenship according to the Citizenship Regulations?","answer":5,"options":[{"label":"Serving in the Canadian military.","value":4},{"label":"Participating in Canadian society, including volunteerism and respect for the environment.","value":5},{"label":"Participating in the Canadian democratic process.","value":6},{"label":"Respecting the rights, freedoms, and obligations set out in the laws of Canada.","value":7}],"reference":"https://www.canada.ca/en/immigration-refugees-citizenship/corporate/publications-manuals/discover-canada/read-online/authorities.html"}]